原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
我叫卡拉·佐·艾尔
My name is Kara Zor-El.
我来自氪星
I'm from Krypton.
我来到这颗星球避难
I'm a refugee on this planet.
翻译     DustD  洗七里  DerbyNinja
我被派往地球保护我的堂弟
I was sent to Earth to protect my cousin.
但我的太空舱被击中后偏离路线
But my pod got knocked off course.
在我到达地球之时
And by the time I got here,
翻译     阿p  左左  C·A
我的堂弟已经长大  成为了超人
my cousin had already grown up and become... Superman.
校对     肉松  饿得慌
我隐藏了我的真实身份
I hid who I really was
直到最近的一起事故
until one day when an accident
迫使我向世界揭示了自己的身份
forced me to reveal myself to the world.
时间轴    想念Gallifrey的Wholock  三水
对于大多数人  我只是凯特科全球媒体公司的记者
To most people, I'm a reporter at CatCo Worldwide Media.
后期     你是不是饿得慌
但私下里  我与收养家庭的姐姐一同为超查部工作
But in secret I work with my adopted sister at the DEO
保护这颗我称之为家园的星球
to protect this planet I call my home
总监     你是不是饿得慌
不受任何人的伤害
from anyone that means to cause it harm.
我是超女
I am Supergirl.
《超女》前情提要
Previously on Supergirl...
我辞职之后
As I step down,
将由副总统贝克担任总司令
I put my full confidence in Vice President Baker
我对他充满信心
as Commander-in-Chief.
大众对外星人的态度正在改变
The climate towards the aliens is changing.
但我不能和你并肩作战  抱歉
But I cannot fight with you. I'm sorry.
那些蟑螂想要变成我们  詹森特工
Those roaches want to be us, Agent Jensen.
他们为了我们的星球而来
They came for our planet.
而你的工作是保护我们的星球
And your job is to protect that.
十分感谢你们的帮助
Your assistance will be greatly noted.
地球第一
Earth first.
那是什么声音
What is that?
是氪石污染警报
It's a Kryptonite contamination alarm.
查出污染源的位置
Find out where.
超女  我们收到了来自纳市的
Supergirl, we've got a Kryptonite alert
-氪石警报  -丹弗斯局长
- somewhere in National City. - Director Danvers...
在我们查明情况之前
You're gonna need to stay back
你暂时不要回来
until we figure out what we're dealing with.
-艾丽克斯  -怎么了
- Alex. - What?
不仅是纳欣诺市  氪石到处都是
It's not just National City. It's everywhere.
超女  你收到了吗
Supergirl, do you read me?
地球第一  地球第一  地球第一
Earth first! Earth first! Earth first!
-艾丽克斯  -荣恩
- Alex. - J'onn!
大气中布满了氪石
The atmosphere was just seeded with Kryptonite.
-什么  -虽然我不清楚是怎么造成的
- What? ‭- Look, I'm not sure how it happened,
但超女之前在从特区往回赶
but Supergirl was flying back from D.C.
我现在联系不上她了
and now, I can't get her on her comms.
她身处遥远的大气之中  荣恩
She's way out in the atmosphere, J'onn,
最后一次探测到她的信号是在内华达州
and the last known signal from her was in Nevada.
我去找她
I'm on it.
快出现  超女
Come on, Supergirl.
你在哪里
Where are you?
我找到她了
I've got her.
她在急速下坠
She's falling fast.
荣恩  你在哪里
Come on, J'onn, where are you?
-他离得太远了  -他会找到她的
- He's too far. - He'll make it.
如果他找不到  这么强的氪石辐射
If he doesn't, with the Kryptonite radiation,
会要了她的命
the impact will kill her.
加油  找到超女
Come on. Get our girl.
超女
我找到你了
I've got you.
荣恩             超女
好棒
Yes!
艾丽克斯  她情况不妙  我这就赶回去
Alex, she's in bad shape. I'm coming in hot.
超 女
第四季 第三集
糟糕
Oh, no, no.
我们要尽快把她转移到干净的房间
We need to get her to a clean room, stat.
那样也没用
It won't do any good.
整个大气瞬间遭到了辐射
The entire atmosphere was irradiated in an instant.
-哪儿都不安全  -我们必须想想办法
- Nowhere is safe. - We have to do something.
黄太阳辐射应该有帮助
Yellow sun radiation should help.
好  我们这就去
Yeah, okay, let's do it.
什么东西能造成这种后果
What could do something like this?
铅粉散播器
The lead dispersal device.
我们用来击溃达克萨姆人的那台仪器
The one that we used to knock out the Daxamites?
不太可能  那台设备被锁在部里
Yeah, unlikely. That device is here under lock and key.
只有超查部特工才能...
Only a DEO Agent could...
詹森
Jensen.
阿斯特拉的反氪石护盾呢
What about Astra's anti-Kryptonite shield?
你们还有反氪石护盾吗
You have an anti-Kryptonite shield?
温对它做了改造  就为了在这种时候派上用场
Winn adapted it for moments just like this.
它可以将她体内的氪石清理干净
It can leech the Kryptonite out of her system.
-在97号保险库  -我去拿
- Vault 97. - I'll get it.
启动太阳灯
Activate the sun lamps.
好了
Okay.
他刚才说的"詹森"是什么意思
What did he mean "Jensen"?
我们出现了安全漏洞
We had a security breach.
总统的袭击者越狱了
The President's attackers, they escaped custody,
一名超查部的新特工帮了他们
and one of our DEO recruits, he helped them.
荣恩  我能解决这件事
J'onn, I can fix this.
我也能治好她
I can fix her.
我一定要让我妹妹好起来
I am not losing my sister today.
我拿来了
I've got it.
她惊厥了
She's seizing.
-为什么不起作用呢  -要等一会才行
- Why isn't it working? - It just needs more time.
什么样的人能做出这种事
What kind of person is capable of doing this?
在你们每个人的心中
Now, in each and every one of you,
都有一束光  一种精神
there is a light, a spirit
无法被扼杀
that cannot be snuffed out.
不肯放弃
That won't give up.
我绝不会抛弃你们
I will never abandon you.
我在竭尽所能为你们而战
And I am doing everything I can to fight for you
两年前
但我一个人的力量不够
but I can't do it alone.
我也需要你们的帮助
I need your help again.
我需要你们怀有希望
I need you to hope.
可不是嘛
Yeah, sure.
我们都能一步跃过大楼
We can all leap tall buildings in a single bound.
你们能记得你们都可以成为英雄
You will remember that you can all be...
我们还可以把他打得不省人事
And we can punch him into the middle of next week.
我正看着呢
I was watching that.
是边看边骂吧
More like hate-watching it.
乔治别说话  老爸  我觉得看得已经够多了
George. Dad, I think it's quite enough.
电视上不断地重播这段讲话
Show that speech over and over again
就好像这是葛底斯堡演说一样
like it was the Gettysburg Address.
"疯子计划"都过去好几周了
Project Maniac was weeks ago.
-是"大清洗"  -哦对
- It's "Myriad." - Oh, that's right.
大清洗计划
Project Myriad.
什么破名字
Stupid name.
那是谁的责任呢
And who was responsible?
从她母星来的其他蟑螂
Other roaches from her home planet.
彼得  请不要在家里说那种话
Pete, we don't talk like that in this house.
没关系  我在学校有时候也会听到
No, it's fine. I hear it at school sometimes.
这有什么问题  我的意思是
What's the problem? Just saying that,
外星人像打不死的小强
you know, aliens are resilient like cockroaches.
虽然母星毁灭了
A planet may die,
但是他们活了下来  继续危害别处
but they survive and infest someone else's.
-爸  -怎么了
- Dad! - What?
超女的家族入侵了地球
Supergirl's family invades our planet
他们拥有诸神的力量
with the power of gods.
而我们这些小人类就该甩手不管
And all of us little people are just supposed to sit back,
放松心态  怀有希望吗
relax and have hope?
是吗
Is that it?
而且我们的总统还赦免了他们所有人
Meanwhile, our president offers them all amnesty?
赦免
Amnesty.
告诉我  乔治
So, you tell me, Georgie,
这个阴谋到底有多深
how deep does this conspiracy go?
本  你该送你爸去上班了
Ben, I think, maybe, you should drive your dad to work.
我今天就把街对面的外星人工厂给烧了
Firing up that alien factory across the street today.
在已知的二十多个外星世界里
Two dozen known alien worlds,
N金属是目前为止引入地球的
and Nth metal is just the strongest material
最坚硬的材料
brought to Earth from any one of them, by far.
你得想想它的好处才行
It's... Gotta think of the good it can do.
可以造车  盖摩天大楼
Cars, skyscrapers...
它连名字读起来都那么拗口
It doesn't even have a vowel.
你还指望它能支撑住摩天大楼吗
It's supposed to hold up skyscrapers?
我们上周没拿到卢瑟公司的合同
We lost the Luthor Corporation contract last week.
-什么  -我被迫关掉了两座高炉
- What? - I had to shutter two blast furnaces.
接了一些铸雕像的活  勉强维持着
Taking on statue commissions just to make ends meet.
你何不革新一下工厂技术
What if you retrofitted the factory
加工N金属呢
to process Nth metal?
你可以重新培训员工
You could retrain your employees.
这座城市建于钢铁之上
This town was built on steel.
美国钢铁
American steel.
如果你把这层地基抽掉的话
You rip out that foundation,
周围的一切都会随之坍塌
and everything will crumble around it.
你记住我的话
You mark my words.
人们本以为纺织业就是现代社会的尽头了
People thought textiles would be the end of modern society,
可是工业革命
but the Industrial Revolution,
创造了前所未有的机会
it created unprecedented opportunities--
我不是你的学生  本
I'm not one of your students, Ben.
我提醒你
And I'll remind you,
它被称为"革命"是有原因的
it was called a "revolution" for a reason.
我还要提醒你
And I'll also remind you,
正是炼钢赚来的钱
that steel is what paid for that
支付了你的大学学费
fancy college education of yours,
但你似乎只有在赐教你老爸的时候
that you seem to only wanna use when you wanna
才舍得搬出你的大学教育
condescend to your old man.
我的大学念得很值  对吧  老爸
Worth every penny. Right, Dad?
不太值
Not so much.
听我说
Listen.
你是我认识的最坚强的人
You're the strongest guy I know.
比N金属还强
You're stronger than Nth metal.
你的工人们也很坚强  我...
Your workers are strong, too. I just...
你会想出办法  渡过难关的
You're gonna figure something out. It's gonna be okay.
你等着瞧好了
You'll see.
快走  快走  咱们去拦住他们
Come on, come on. Come on, let's go stop them.
我们要让那群外星人关门歇业
We've gotta shut down those aliens.
-拦住那些蟑螂  -快点
- Stop those roaches! - Hurry up!
拦住那辆卡车
Stop that truck!
下来
Get down!
出什么事了
What's going on here?
萨克  萨克  这到底是怎么回事
Thack! Thack, what the hell is going on here?
我们不能让他们毁了这座城市  本
We're not gonna let them kill this town, Ben.
-什么  不  -我们不能让他们得逞
- What? No! - We won't let them.
等等  不不不
Wait! No, no, no, no.
爸  爸  你得出面阻止
Dad! Dad, you gotta stop this.
他们是你的员工  他们听你的
They're your employees. They'll listen to you.
-爸  -拜托
- Dad! - Please!
我们也是工人  跟你们一样
We are workers, same as you.
他有尖刺
He's got spikes!
不  不要  不要
No! No! No, no, no.
伙计们  听我说  他就长这个样子
Guys, guys, listen to me! It's just the way he looks!
他就长这个样子  没关系  没关系
It's just the way he looks! It's okay, it's okay.
-我是和平主义  -好了  大家都冷静
- I come in peace! - Okay, let's just all calm down.
都讲点道理
And be reasonable.
我不是故意的
I didn't mean to!
我不是故意的  我不是故意的
I didn't mean to! I didn't mean to!
谁去叫救护车
Someone call an ambulance!
撑着点  撑着点
Hey, stay with me. Stay with me.
是超女吗
Is it Supergirl?
不  是联调局的艾丽克斯·丹弗斯特工
No. Agent Alex Danvers. FBI.
超女被叫走了  恐怕只能由我来照顾你了
Supergirl got called away. Afraid you're stuck with me.
伤得很严重吗
Is it... is it bad?
远不及你和你朋友对那个巴维克人下手狠
Not half as bad as what you and your friends did to that Bravik.
什么  不不不  我只是...
What? No, no, no. No, I was just--
我是想帮忙的
I was trying to help
但是我们的人很愤怒  还很害怕
but our guys are just angry. They are scared, they're--
-你们的人  -我的家人
- Your guys? - My family,
街对面的钢铁工厂是我们家开的
we own the steel factory across the way.
那些工人  他们都是好人
The workers, they're very good people.
他们也很幸运
Oh, they are lucky people.
因为超女对他们下手非常轻
Because Supergirl went very, very easy on them.
保持伤口清洁  勤换绷带
Keep it clean, change the bandage often,
别再惹麻烦了
and stay out of trouble.
对他们下手非常轻
Went very, very easy on them?
联调局应该为人民服务
The FBI are supposed to work for the people.
确实  我们为美国人民服务
Indeed, we work for the American people
而根据《外星人赦免法》
and per the Alien Amnesty Act--
外星  外星人
Alien. Alien?
你的工人们袭击的是一名美国人
The man your workers just attacked is an American.
他与你一样拥有安全工作的权利
He has just as much right to work here safely as you.
他用尖刺射伤了我的儿子
He impaled my son with a freak spike.
我想你所说的是
I think you're talking about
他的生物防御机制
his biological defense mechanism.
生物什么  那是故意袭击
Biological what? It was an assault!
那你管这叫什么
What do you call this?
超女刚刚在菲戈大街与第八大街
Supergirl was just attacked
遭到了失窃外星武器的袭击
with stolen alien weaponry on Fig and 8th.
温说她没事  但是...
Winn said that she's okay, but...
好了  咱们走  走吧
All right. Let's move it out! Let's go.
你怎么样  儿子  还好吗
How are you doing, buddy? Are you all right?
为什么联调局会与超女合作
Why in the world is the FBI working with Supergirl?
真正的问题是
The real question is,
为什么他们要一同对抗我们
why are they working against us?
看看我们能不能为儿童医院做点事
See if we can do something for the children's hospital.
或许举办一场募捐晚会能有帮助
Maybe a fundraising gala would help?
卢瑟女士  我能和你谈谈吗
Ms. Luthor, could I have a word with you?
求你了  是关于我父亲的公司
Please. It's about my father's company,
洛克伍德家族钢厂
Lockwood Family Steel.
等等  没事的
Wait, wait, it's okay.
我有什么能帮到你
Hi, how can I help you?
真抱歉这样拦下你
Hi, I am so sorry to ambush you like this.
但要联系到你可不容易
You're not exactly an easy person to reach.
我是有意如此的  不过...
Well, that's by design, but...
洛克伍德钢铁  你是彼得·洛克伍德的儿子
Lockwood Steel. You're Peter Lockwood's son?
是的  我是本·洛克伍德
Yeah, I'm Ben Lockwood and, uh...
好吧  二十年来  洛克伍德钢铁被应用于
Okay. For 20 years, Lockwood Steel has been used
卢瑟公司的多个成功产品
in some of Luthor Corp's most successful products.
是的  没错
Well, yeah, that is true,
但我要提醒你的是  我们正在重塑品牌
but in case you weren't aware, we are rebranding.
为了让L公司继续保持成功
And in order for L-Corp to remain successful,
它必须跟上时代
it has to stay current.
N金属制成的钢铁才是未来
Steel made with Nth metal is the future.
历史难道不是也很重要吗
Shouldn't the past matter, too?
你可以这么看  你父亲可以借此机会
Look at it this way. This is an opportunity for your father
对工厂和工人进行现代化改革
to modernize the plant, and his work force.
是的  但我们工厂的机器耗费了上百万美元
Well, yeah, but those machines cost millions of dollars.
你父亲是个生意人  而且很有生意头脑
Your father is a businessman, and a good one.
进步的大军行动起来了
Just because it's the march of progress,
不意味着他就要被落下
doesn't mean he has to be left behind.
纳欣诺市大学
昭昭天命
Manifest Destiny.
这是美国19世纪中叶不可阻挡的
That was the name of America's unstoppable push west
十四个月前
"西进运动"的口号  是"进步"
during the mid 1800s. It's "Progress..."
N金属
类似钢铁
但更坚硬
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
我想要脱稿讲点东西
I'm gonna go off script a little bit.
进步  你们怎么看待进步
Progress. What do we think of progress?
没有持续的发展与进步
Without continual growth and progress,
改善  成就与成功之类的概念
notions such as improvement, achievement, and success,
就没有意义
have no meaning.
这不是我说的  是本·富兰克林
That's not me. That's Ben Franklin.
但我要说的重点是
But my point is,
自从建国开始
ever since the beginning,
我们的领袖就执迷于进步
our leaders had been obsessed with progress.
但你能告诉我进步有什么好处吗
But can you tell me what's so great about it?
发现了新大陆
Well, the discovery of the New World,
这也是进步  对吗
that's progress, right?
对西班牙和哥伦布来说是
For Spain and Columbus.
对美洲原住民来说可不是
No so much for the Native Americans.
马斯丁总统的《外星人赦免法》
President Marsdin's Alien Amnesty Act.
那是进步吗
Is that progress?
我认为是进步  对吗  当然是
I think it's progress, right? Of course, it is.
但我知道一些美国人不这样认为
But I know some Americans who don't think so.
事实上  我知道一些美国人因此过得更糟
In fact, I know some Americans who are worse off for it.
我想表达什么观点呢
So, what's my point?
下次有人告诉你进步有多伟大时
The next time someone tells you how great progress is,
我希望你能停下想一想
I want you to stop a moment, I want you to think
是谁为进步付出了代价
about who paid the price for it.
好了  下课了  都出去吧
Okay, get out of here, get out of here.
生极科技事件仍未降温
The fallout continues for Biomax Technology
该公司上个月被曝光欺骗消费者
exposed last month for touting a fraudulent,
该设计可能致命
and possibly fatal design...
爸  你怎么回家了
Dad! What are you doing home?
我把它关了
I shut it down.
-又关了一座高炉  -是整间工厂
- Oh, not another blaster. - Whole factory.
什么
What?
他去银行贷款  被拒绝了
He went to the bank for the loan. They said no.
让他们去死  所有人去死
Hell with them and everyone else.
天啊  爸
Oh, God, Dad, um...
-我很遗憾  -少来
- I am so sorry. - Spare me.
做人太软弱  不肯起身抗争
This is what happens when you're too soft,
就是这个下场
when you don't stand up and fight.
抗争  爸  和谁抗争
Fight... Dad, fight who?
-你知道和谁  -那些害虫
- You know who. - The roaches.
-乔治  -乔治
- George! - George!
抱歉
Sorry.
好吧  我们或许积蓄不多
Okay, we might not have much,
但我们还有这幢房子  我们可以...
but we still have the house. We can...
我们可以做第二抵押  我去和银行谈
We can get a second mortgage. I'm gonna go talk to the bank.
谈  你就只会谈  对不对
Talk. That's mostly what you do, right?
谈谈谈
Talk, talk, talk.
可你真正该做的
When what you should be doing,
是出去拿出点男人样
is go out there-- and be a man.
爸  冷静点  好吗
Dad, calm down, all right?
你喝多了
You're drunk.
地球人  不要惊慌
People of Earth, do not be afraid.
我们为和平而来
We come in peace.
我们跨越星海
We have crossed a sea of stars
来带你们走上一条新的道路
in order to bring you a new way...
你接着说啊
You were saying?
更好的道路
...A better way.
瞧瞧  金罗美
Look at that. Gin rummy.
你肯定出老千了
Okay, I'm 100% sure you're cheating.
我们情况如何  这些食物大概够吃一周
Okay, so, what have we got? This is maybe a week of food,
限量配给的话或许够吃两周
maybe two if we ration it.
是啊  但水就快用光了
Yeah, but we're running out of water.
大概还能用三四天
We have three, maybe four days.
我们之前没把浴缸装满水吗
Didn't we fill the tub?
装了
Yes.
我想我们或许应该离开
I think maybe we should leave.
离开
Leave?
-可这是我们的家  -是啊
- This is our home. - Yeah, it is,
但很快就要断粮断水了
but it's quickly running out of food and water.
我们无处可去
There is nowhere for us to go.
达克萨姆人设立了检查点
The Daxamites have set up checkpoints.
好吧  那我们能开多远开多远
Okay, then we drive as far as we can.
或许我们能避开检查点  到沿海城市
Maybe we can sneak around the checkpoints, get to Coast City
但我们必须试试看
but we have to try something.
试试看  是啊
Try something? Yeah.
我们为什么不试试这样  为什么不留下
How about we try this? How about we stay
为属于我们的东西抗争
and we fight for what's ours?
这是我们的家  本  我们不是难民
This is our home, Ben. We're not refugees.
爸  我们就在这等着
Dad, just wait here.
超女会来救我们的
Supergirl will come and save us.
不  她不会的
No! No, she won't,
因为超女和那些入侵者一样是外星人
because Supergirl is an alien just like the invaders.
抗争  爸  用什么抗争
And fight, Dad? Fight with what?
我们的全部家当都在这里
Because all we have is right here.
但你知道吗  没关系
But you know what? That's okay.
因为我们是一家人
Because we're a family.
我们可以一家人齐心合力
And we can come together as a family.
爸  你和乔治去拿包
So, Dad, you and Georgie get the bags.
莉迪娅  去发动车子  我去拿补给品
Lydia, ready the car. I'll get the supplies.
听我说  我们能挺过去的
Hey, listen. We can do this.
你是个好男人  本·洛克伍德
You're a good man, Ben Lockwood.
你也是个好妻子
You're not so bad yourself.
快走
Go!
-后退  -快走  快走
- Get back! - Go! Go!
我的单车
My bike!
没关系  没关系
It's okay, it's okay, it's okay.
你们安全了
You're safe, now.
他们走了
They're gone...
下一个问题
Next question.
凯特·格兰特新闻发布会
十二个月前
大胡子  问吧
All right, long beard, go ahead.
随着白宫翻修工作的开始
With the White House renovations coming along,
总统想把蓝屋粉刷成什么颜色
what color is the President intending to paint the Blue Room?
蓝色
Blue.
谁能给我拿点止痛药来吗
Can somebody please bring me some Ibuprofen?
我觉得有点头疼
I feel a bit of a headache coming on.
奥尔森先生
Mr. Olsen?
伊芙  你能确认一下市区银行抢劫案现场
Eve, can you make sure that we have a reporter downtown
是否有我们的记者吗
for the bank robbery?
我们不能指望卡拉全城到处跑
We can't expect Kara to be everywhere, all over--
这位是纳市大学的洛克伍德教授
This is Professor Lockwood from NCU.
记不记得他要求与你进行五分钟的会面
Remember he asked for five minutes?
对
Right.
谢谢你肯这么仓促地与我见面
Thank you for seeing me on such short notice.
没问题  我总是有时间接见我们的读者
Not a problem. I always have time for our subscribers.
-请坐  -好
- Please have a seat. - Yeah.
有什么能帮你的吗
What can I help you with?
那我就直接问了
Well, I'll just ask you.
凯特科为什么不报道外星人攻击
Why doesn't CatCo cover the impact of extraterrestrial attacks
对普通公民的影响
on your average citizen?
听你这么说我很惊讶
I'm surprised to hear you say that
因为我们尽了最大的努力
because we make our best effort
去报道每条新闻的每个侧面
to cover every side of every story.
我们对达克萨姆人入侵以及余波的报道
And our coverage on the Daxamite invasion
还为我们赢得了普利策奖
and its aftermath did win us a Pulitzer.
这我知道  那是篇文笔优美的文章
I'm aware of that. It's a very beautifully-written article,
但它写得好像这件事完结了似的
but it treats the story like it's over and done with.
在我住的社区里  人们丢了工作
In my neighborhood, people have lost their jobs,
损失了财产  失去了...
people have lost possessions, people have lost...
失去了家园
People have lost their homes.
对不起  这周坏事频发
I'm sorry, it's been a hell of a week.
那我说一些令你吃惊的事吧
Let me just blow your mind here, okay?
业主保险
Home owner's insurance.
你知道外星人入侵其实不在保险范围内吗
Did you know that it doesn't actually cover alien invasion?
-谁知道呢  -我们知道
- Who knew? - We did,
因为我们在商业版里报道过
because we covered that in our business section.
对  但那是很久以前的事了
Right, and that's all the way in the back,
它把普通人变成了数字和统计数据
and it turns the common person into numbers and statistics.
我来这是告诉你  在这些数字的背后
I am here to tell you that there are people
是活生生的人
behind these numbers.
那些人正在受苦
People who are hurting,
如果你们也能报道他们的事
and it would be so very helpful
那会帮上他们的大忙
if you would just tell their stories, too.
洛克伍德教授  很感谢你的立场
Professor Lockwood, I appreciate your position,
对于你的遭遇  我表示遗憾
and I'm very sorry for what you've been going--
你有听到我说的话吗
Did you hear anything that I--
这不仅关系到我
This isn't about just me.
奥尔森先生  莉娜·卢瑟打来电话
Mr. Olsen, I have Lena Luthor on the line for you.
我们的谈话不得不结束了
I have to cut this short,
但你提出了一些合理的观点
but you make some valid points
我会告诉卢瑟小姐的
and I'll bring them up to Ms. Luthor.
莉娜·卢瑟  她和这些有什么关系
Lena Luthor. What the hell does she have to do with any of this?
我不知道你是否听说了  她现在是这里的老板
I'm not sure if you heard, but she runs this place now.
卢瑟小姐  不  我现在不忙
Ms. Luthor. No, I'm not busy right now.
本土主义者
Nativist.
六个月前
一个常用于贬义的词
Term often used in a derogatory fashion
用来形容那些害怕外人的人
to describe those who fear the other.
问你们一个问题
Question for you.
那些想要保护自己家园不受外来者入侵的人
What's wrong with those who wish to protect their homes
有错吗
from the outsiders?
美国是一个移民国家
Well, America is a country of immigrants.
没错  但是这点一直都有争议性
Yes, but that's always been controversial.
在1775年  本杰明·富兰克林本人
You see, in 1775, Benjamin Franklin himself
写到他自己对移民的恐惧
writes of his own fears of immigrants whom he warned,
移民永远无法接受我们的文化或习俗
"The immigrant will never adopt our language or customs
正如他们无法获得我们的肤色一样
any more than he could acquire our complexion."
富兰克林当时说的是德国移民
Franklin was talking about German immigrants
而且当时美国还是英国的殖民地
back when America was still a British colony.
我看不出这话如何能套用在其他地方
I don't see how it applies to anything.
我明白这个观点为什么会有问题
I can see why this point of view would be problematic,
尤其是在我们说到人类移民的时候
especially since we are talking about human immigrants.
过去的两百年来  无论何种肤色的
Human immigrants, who, for the past 200 years,
人类移民成就了美国的伟大
made America great no matter what their complexion.
但是现在  我们欢迎的
But now, we welcome immigrants
不仅是他国移民
not only from outside our borders,
还有外星移民
but from beyond our atmosphere.
那我问问你们
So, let me just ask you...
人类工人如何与其竞争
How does the human worker compete?
有人能回答吗  人类工人如何与外星人竞争
Anyone? How does the human worker compete against an alien
外星人毫不费力地
who could lift two tons of steel
就能将两吨重的钢铁扛在肩上
over its head without even breaking a sweat.
人类工人如何与一个
How does the human worker compete
能跨海岸空运货物的外星人竞争
against an alien that can fly goods from one coast to the other,
而我们的卡车就只能放着生锈
leaving our trucks to rust away in the sand.
抱歉  教授  讲到哪一页了
Sorry, Professor, what page are we on?
本·富兰克林的担忧成真了
Ben Franklin's fears have come to pass.
现代移民无法融入
The modern immigrant cannot assimilate
而这不是意愿的问题
and it's not a question of desire,
也不是文化的问题
not a question of culture,
这是生物学的问题  就此来看
it is a question of biology. And from that context...
就此来看
From that context,
说我本土主义
I should be proud
我会感到自豪
if you were to call me a nativist.
这不是本土主义  这是仇外
This isn't nativism. It's xenophobia.
这话从你这肤色的人嘴里说出来
I can't say I'm surprised to hear that
我一点也不意外
from someone with your complexion.
我们又收到对你课程的投诉了  本
We've had another complaint about your class, Ben.
-这些年轻人啊  -但确实
- Uh-oh. Millennials. - Still.
你讲课似乎太极端了
It sounds like your lectures are extreme.
历史是极端的  真理也是极端的
Well, history is extreme, truth is extreme.
课堂不是一个安全港湾
The classroom isn't a safe space
让老师把童话版的事实讲给学生听
where everyone gets to hear a fairy tale version of the facts.
如果学生没法接受
And if students can't handle perspectives
与自己不同的观点
that are different than their own,
那我也没办法  也许他们不该在这里学习
then I don't know. Maybe they don't belong here.
学校董事会可不这么想
The tenure board would disagree.
-这是什么意思  -关于你课堂上的言论
- What are you saying? - You've been warned multiple times
学校已经警告你很多次了
about the rhetoric in your class.
我们认为你应该无偿离职
Now, we think you should take a leave of absence without pay.
你知道我家里的情况
You know what my family is going through.
我不能失去这份工作
I can't lose this job.
你这是把你自己的偏见
You're passing on your own prejudice
教给学生  本
to our students, Ben.
这是一所大学  一所多样化的大学
We're a university, a diverse one.
听着  我很抱歉  我一直挺喜欢你
Look, I'm sorry. I've always liked you,
但这是你自找的
but you brought this on yourself.
沃伦主任  听我说  我...
Dean Warren, look, I'm...
不敢相信他们竟然
I still can't believe they haven't rounded up
还没抓到从阿尔巴特洛斯湾潜逃的犯人
all those escaped convicts from Albatross Bay.
说实话  那疯狂哥特妹
Honestly, after that crazy goth chick
差点把他们烤焦在监狱里
tried frying them all in their cells
他们也应该休个假了
they probably deserve a little furlough.
你认识这人吗
Do you know this guy?
洛克伍德教授  你跟踪我到这来的吗
Professor Lockwood? Did you follow me here?
是你告我的状吗  玻璃心
Did you tattle on me, Snowflake?
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
我在说什么  行  我说你肤色的事
What am I talking about? Okay, look, the complexion thing.
算我错了  我道歉
I'm sorry, I apologize,
但你非得害我被开除吗  这是我的工作
but you had to get me fired? This is my job.
我的生计  我还要养家
This is my livelihood. I have a family!
我什么都没说
I didn't say anything,
但别人说了也不奇怪
but I'm not surprised someone did.
别人  对啊  因为我实在太过分了
Oh! Someone. Absolutely! Because I was so out of line!
你看看你  你不正常
Look at you. You are not okay.
我不用你同情
Okay, I don't need your pity--
-没什么问题吧  -没
- Hey, everything okay here? - Yeah.
你又不是外星人  来这里干嘛
You're not an alien. What are you doing here?
今天是卡拉OK之夜  我问你一下
It's karaoke night. Let me ask you something.
我要唱野兽男孩的歌吗
Should I do Beastie Boys?
你觉得我能唱好吗
Do you think I could pull that off?
不行的话  那就唱托托的《非洲》
It's either that, or Africa by Toto.
我不是在跟你说这个
That's not really not what I'm talking about.
我说的是  你是人类而他们不是
I'm talking about you're human and they are not,
-他们很危险  -你说的"他们"是什么意思
- and they are dangerous. - What do you mean by "They"?
小强
Roaches.
你不知道我在说什么  她知道
You don't know what I'm talking about? She does.
我们不对外星人动手动脚
We don't touch aliens.
告诉你吧  我们不对任何人动手动脚
Actually, you know what? We don't touch anyone.
所以你那双手最好老实点
So, why don't you keep your hands to yourself
嘴巴放干净点
and watch that mouth.
行  你个地球叛徒
Got it. Yeah. Earth traitor.
多谢帮忙
Thanks for the backup.
不客气
Yeah. Anytime.
顺便说下  你可一定得唱野兽男孩的
And for the record, definitely Beastie Boys.
我就知道
I knew it.
打扰一下  先生  您关注时事吗
Excuse me, sir, are you a concerned citizen?
四个月前
您为孩子担忧吗
Hi, are you concerned for your children?
您对超女和联邦调查局
Hi, are you concerned that Supergirl works with the FBI
联手对付政敌感到担忧吗
to round up political enemies?
您对...  看路啊
Hi, are you... You just watch it.
抱歉  我的错  意外而已
Sorry. My bad. It's just an accident.
是意外吗
Was it, though?
-管你呢  哥们  -行  赶紧走吧
- Whatever, dude. - Okay. Walk away!
给我拿一张
I'll take one of those.
继续传播善言啊  兄弟
Keep spreading the good word, brother.
谢了
Thank you.
天  又来
Oh, God. Not again.
-你们安全吗  -我们没事
- Are you safe? - We're fine.
-但是你父亲  -为什么  他怎么了
- But your dad... - Why? What about him?
我没法联系到他  我不知道他在哪里
I can't reach him. I don't know where he is.
我知道他在哪里了
I think I have an idea.
父亲  父亲
Dad! Dad!
我的天  父亲
Oh, my God. Dad!
爸
Dad!
我会把你救出去的
I'm gonna get you out of here.
-你做不到  -好的  你没错
- You can't. - Okay. You're right, you're right.
我会把这个举起来
I'm gonna lift this up,
你就从下面钻出来  好吗
and you just slip off out from under, okay?
一  二  三
One, two, three!
你不是超女
You're not Supergirl.
不  我可以的  父亲  我可以救你出去
No. No. I can do this, Dad. I can get you out of here.
我不想你这么做
I don't want you to.
什么
What?
父亲  你刚刚说什么
Dad, what did you just say?
我故意来这里的  本
I came here on purpose, Ben.
这是我的家
This is my home.
这个钢铁
And this steel...
是我的生命  一直都是
It's my life. Always has been.
现在  它大限将至  我也是
Now, its time is over, and so is mine.
不  别这么说
Hey, hey, no. Don't talk like that.
你还可以活许多年
You've got a lot of years left.
也许是的  但是快乐的时光早已过去
Maybe, but all the good ones are long behind me.
记住我怎么抚养你的  孩子
Remember how I raised you, kid.
-你以同样的方式抚养乔治  -遵命
- And you raise Georgie the same way. - Yes, sir.
记住  挺直身躯
All right? You stand tall.
自豪地活着  你姓洛克伍德
Stand proud. You're a Lockwood.
你是人类  这个星球属于你
You're human. This planet belongs to you.
站起来为自己的东西而战
Stand up and fight for what's yours.
爸爸
Dad!
我爱你  爸爸
I love you, Dad.
我也爱你  现在快走  成为我期待的那样
Love you, too. Now, go, go. Be the man I raised you to be.
有时候  生活中发生的事
Sometimes, things happen in life
我们无法解释
that we can't explain.
比如一个善良的人过早去世
Like a good man being sent to an early grave.
这些事发生时
And when, not if, these things happen,
会让我们觉得想要放弃
it can make us feel like we want to give up.
所以  我很乐意读给你们听
So, I'm very happy to read to you,
我父亲最喜欢的名言
my father's favorite quote.
这是他知道的唯一一句名言
Well, it's the only quote he knew.
温斯顿·丘吉尔
Winston Churchill.
决不屈服
"Never give in.
Never give in.
不向任何事物低头  无论大事小事
Never, in nothing, great or small,
无论要事琐事
large or petty,
除了对于荣誉和智慧的信念
except in considerations of honor and good sense.
绝不向强权屈服
Never yield to force,
绝不向敌人的强大攻势屈服
or the apparently overwhelming might of the enemy that confronts you.
绝不  绝不  绝对不
Never. Never, ever
屈服
give in."
你真有胆量到这里来
Well, you certainly have some nerve coming here.
我只是想表达我的敬意
I just wanted to pay my respects.
你在我寻求帮助时
You had the chance to give respect
有机会表达敬意
when I asked for help.
但现在  我父亲去世了  所以我们不需要
But now, my dad's gone, so, we don't need it.
好的  本  听着  与你的工厂无关
Okay, Ben, listen, this isn't about your factory.
这事关你和你的家庭
This is about you and your family
以及你父亲的工人
and your father's workers.
时局艰难
Times are tough,
我想以你父亲的名义设立一个基金
and I wanted to set up a fund in your father's name--
-绝对不行  -我只是想帮忙
- Absolutely not. - I'm just trying to help.
你和杀死他的东西一起工作
You work with the things that killed him.
N号金属  外星科技
Nth metal, alien technology?
我听说你有个新的
I hear you got some new
图像装置可以让它们伪装自己
image device that lets them hide what they are.
那真的很变态
That's really sick.
我理解你很生气  好吗
I understand that you're angry, okay?
但是你不能沿这条路走下去
But you can't go down this path.
因为自己的问题怪别人
Blaming other people for your problems,
你会和我哥哥一个下场
you will just end up like my brother.
它们不是人类
They're not people.
很棒的演讲  小本  和我们去喝酒怎么样
Nice speech, Benny. What do you say, you join us for a beer?
好的  好的
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
谢谢你雇我们修理这地方  本
Hey, thanks for hiring us to patch up your place, Ben.
工厂关闭后就很难找工作了
Jobs have been scarce since the factory shut.
工作很难找是因为那些小强
Jobs are scarce because of the roaches.
完全没错
Damn right.
记得你爸说过的  本  "永不放弃"
Remember what your old man said, Ben. "Never give up."
怪物仍旧存在
The fact that monstrosity is still standing,
这颗星球已经腐坏
while this place has been left to rot,
这是对我们的侮辱
it's an insult to us all.
如果我们有所行动呢
What if we did something?
说真的  要是我们有所行动呢
Seriously, what if we did something?
就像老爸总说的  "你可以嘴上不停说
It's like Dad always said, "You can talk, talk, talk.
但早晚  一个人得站起来才是人
Sooner or later, a man's gotta stand up and be a man!
而且他必须战斗"
And he's gotta fight."
说得好听  但是我们能做什么呢
That's all well and good, but what can we do?
我不知道
I don't know.
我们把它烧掉怎么样
What if we burn it down?
过来  过来  好
Come on. Come on. Okay.
好了  先生们  我们来点火吧
All right, gentlemen, let's light 'em up.
我已经搞定了一个
I already got one.
不要鲁莽行动  安全第一  我来教你们怎么做
No sloppy work. Safety first. I'll show you how it's done.
看啊  烧着了
Look at it burn!
现在比钢还硬了吧
Stronger than steel now?
我不能呼吸了
I can't breathe.
不  他是人类
Oh, no, he's human.
-厄尔  厄尔  -我去找人帮忙
- Earl! Earl! - I'll go get help.
他有换脸器
He's got a face changer.
别动  别动  我记得你
Don't move. Don't move. I remember you.
他很危险
He's dangerous.
不  我不危险  我是个楼层经理
No, I'm not. I'm a floor manager.
不  你不是的
No, you're not.
-你是外星人  -不要啊
- You're an alien. - Don't.
我其实碰到过他一次
I actually met him once,
我当时想  "这个人很温柔"
and I thought, "This guy is soft."
两个月前
但是我说不好  可能我错了
But I don't know. Maybe I'm wrong.
可能这正是我们所需要的
Maybe this is exactly what we need.
我们需要人类来保护人类
We need humans protecting humans.
当开国元勋们说
I mean, when the Founding Fathers said,
"人人生而平等"
"All men are created equal,"
他们指的是什么  是人啊
what did they mean? They meant men.
他们并不是指来自太空的蟑螂
They didn't mean some roach from the vacuum of space.
老天  如果本杰明·富兰克林还活着
I mean, my God, if Benjamin Franklin were alive today,
他会为保护玛多利亚人的权利
would he have protected the right of some Maaldorian
而让他们取代你的工作吗  萨克
to take your job, Thack?
-当然不  -绝对不会
- Hell no. - Hell no, no, no.
他会保护你的
He would have defended you.
能给我一点时间吗  把这些发出去
Can you give me a second? Just pass those out.
各位  我去去就回
I'll be right back, everyone.
沃伦主任
Dean Warren.
本  你好吗
Ben. How are you?
我很好  非常好  你呢
I'm good. I'm very good. How are you?
真希望我也能这样说
Wish I could say the same.
课堂上人满为患  预算正在削减
Classes are overcrowded, budget's being cut.
明妮和我也失去房子了
Minnie and I lost the house, too.
-不  不会吧  -那个创世纪事件
- Oh, no, no. - That genesis event.
-外星环境改造  -是啊
- Terraforming. - Right.
我们现在住在学生住宅
We're in student housing now.
-我肯定明妮会喜欢  -是的
- Oh, I'm sure Minnie loves that. - Yeah.
听着  本
Look, Ben,
你在大学发生的事
I'm sorry for what happened
-我很抱歉  -不
- with you and the University. - Oh! No.
不  把你那样扫地出门是不对的
No, it was wrong throwing you out on the street like that.
我不觉得我们之中有人理解
I don't think any of us understood
你所经历的事情  但是现在...
what you were going through, but now...
现在很多人都在经历一样的事
Now, a lot of people are going through the same thing.
事情正发生在我们身上
Well, what's happening is happening to us,
给了我们力量
and that gives us power,
意味着我们可以反击
that means that we can fight back.
事实上  我和一些朋友
As a matter of fact, me and some friends,
我们聚在一起
we are putting together
像是个互助小组
something like a support group,
我非常希望你能加入我们
and I would like very much for you to join us.
洛克伍德教授
Professor Lockwood.
你又是谁
Well, that depends on who's asking.
知道你和你的朋友们
Someone who knows that you and your friends
在过去几个月里
have been harassing alien immigrants
骚扰外星移民的人
for the last couple of months.
伤害他们  杀戮他们
Hurting them, killing them.
进来吧
Get in.
所以你就是在晚上出来活跃的那个东西
So, you're the thing that goes bump in the night.
好了  听着  我真的不知道
Okay, listen, I don't really know
你在说什么
what you're talking about.
你们很棒
You boys are good.
但是你们太鲁莽了
But you're sloppy.
我们找到了部分指纹
We found a partial fingerprint
就在你用来打布莱维克头部的管子上
in the pipe you used to beat over the head of that Bravik.
还找到了你的DNA
And we found your DNA in the dirt
就在玛多利亚双胞胎遗体旁的泥土里
next to the bodies of those Maaldorian twins.
他们把你伤得很重吧  但是你伤他们更重
They got you good, huh? But you got them better.
这个在下一次会有用的
This should help for next time.
如果你会逮捕我  我为什么还需要防弹衣
Why would I need body armor if you're gonna arrest me?
我不会逮捕你  你干得太棒了
I'm not gonna arrest you. You've done such great work.
我来这是为了告诉你  我们需要合作
I'm here to tell you that we need to work together.
人们爱戴你  本
People love you, Ben.
你有着罕见的沟通天赋
You have a rare gift of communication,
就像富兰克林·罗斯福  又或者是墨索里尼
like Franklin Roosevelt or Mussolini.
我的同事  他们都没有这样的天赋
The people I work with, they don't have such gifts.
我们要是联手
But I think if we could all work together,
就能让这个国家变得更好
we could make this country a much better place.
怎么做
How?
我们要揭发总统
We're gonna expose the president
他说谎  诈骗  还是个外星人
as a liar, a fraud, and an alien.
上爆料微博看看  好吗
Read a little 4chan, do ya?
我知道你不相信我
I can understand why you wouldn't believe me.
要是我们能证明这是真的话
But can you imagine if we proved it was true?
这个世界都会为此改变
How that would change the world?
那确实是个好梦
Well, that's a nice dream,
但我都不知道你是谁
but I don't even know who you are.
默茜·格雷夫斯
Mercy Graves.
那是我弟弟  奥蒂斯
And that's my brother, Otis.
有事吗
What's up?
最重要的是  这是菲奥纳
And most importantly, this is Fiona.
兼职酒保
Part-time bartender,
全职是倡导外星人权利的激进分子
full-time alien rights activist.
别被长相所迷惑了
Don't be fooled by the lipstick.
这副皮囊之下就是个怪物
Beneath the disguise, she's a monster.
她组织其他怪物
One who is organizing other monsters
来对抗我们
to defend themselves against us.
但这些都还好
But that's okay.
因为有些畜生的能力
Because some of these creatures
我们可以加以利用
have skills we can use.
你什么打算
So, what do you say?
加入我们吗
Besties?
洛克伍德家族钢厂
快趴下
Get down!
地球第一  地球第一  地球第一
Earth first! Earth first! Earth first!
现今
黄太阳辐射在帮助
The yellow sun radiation is helping
护盾抵抗氪石
the shield counteract the Kryptonite.
但是不够快
But not fast enough.
那你有什么建议
So, what are you saying?
除非我们能设法
Unless we could somehow get her
让她离开地球大气层
out of Earth's very atmosphere,
不然  很快我们就会无能为力
soon, there won't be anything we can do for her.
那我们就这样做  蒙·艾尔就成功了
Then, that's what we do. I mean, it worked for Mon-El.
我们把她放进分离舱
Then we can just put her in a pod,
送她去阿尔戈市
and we can send her to Argo City.
不行  超女已经被辐射了
Negative. Supergirl's already been irradiated.
她太虚弱了
She's too weak.
艾丽克斯  如果我们把她带离地球  她会死的
Alex, if we try to take her off-world, she'll die.
我们总得做些什么啊
Well, there must be something I can do.
客观地说
There is, objectively,
在整个可量化的宇宙中
across the entire quantifiable universe,
你什么都做不了
nothing you could do.
那我就要找其他人帮忙了
Then I need to ask somebody else for help.
-莉娜  -她在哪儿
- Lena - Where is she?
在这边
She's this way.
听着  我知道你和超女
Hey, listen, I know that you and Supergirl,
不总是意见一致
you don't always see eye to eye on everything,
但当我们最需要你时  你总能伸出援手
but it means a tremendous amount to us, to me,
这对我们来说意义重大  对我个人也是
that you're always here when we need you the most.
人们低估我了  我其实很关心这些事
People underestimate me, but I care.
真的
I really do.
你来了
You're here.
这是能制造由辐射控制的原型环境
Oh, my. A radiation-controlled proto-environment
内部真空密封的机械外骨骼
housed in a vacuum-sealed, mechanical exoskeleton
里面装有二毫米弹簧的圆盘
contained in a spring-loaded two-millimeter disc.
超女必须待在里面
Supergirl is gonna have to stay inside this
直到我们找到解毒的方法
until we figure out how to detoxify the atmosphere.
而我们现在还完全不知道怎么做
Which we have no idea how to do.
那这就是无限期监禁了
So, this is indefinite confinement?
我们没得选了  就这样吧
We have no other choice, so, do it.
别紧张  他是一伙的
Don't worry. He's with us.
超女死了吗
Is Supergirl dead?
没有正式声明  但是看着挺吓人的
It's nothing official yet, but it looks scary.
还有一件事
Just one more thing.
住手  你在干嘛
Hey, hey! Stop! What are you doing?
-收拾残局  -有时就这样
- Tying up loose ends. - It happens.
不行不行  我们不能杀自己人
No! No, not here. We do not kill our own.
拜托  他就是个路人甲
Oh, please. He's a nobody.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
那这样  你是超查部的  对吧
All right. You're from the DEO, right?
你能把这些人带出来
You got these fine people out.
-是的  -那好
- Yeah. - Good.
那我猜
Well, then I'm gonna assume
你也能把我们领进去
that you can get us all back in.